# Christian S. Ahart

Address 257 Corporation Street Website chrisahart.github.io
London, E15 3DL Email c.ahart@imperial.ac.uk

# **Professional summary**

I have recently joined the group of Dr. Clotilde Cucinotta at Imperial College London as a Research Associate (postdoctoral researcher), working to enable the dynamical modelling of electrochemical systems under applied potential by interfacing the DFT code CP2K with the NEGF code SMEAGOL.

## **Publications**

- 1. **Christian S. Ahart**, Kevin M. Rosso and Jochen Blumberger. Implementation and Validation of Constrained Density Functional Theory Forces in the CP2K Package. *J. Chem. Theory Comput.* 18, 4438–4446, 2022.
- 2. **Christian S. Ahart**, Kevin M. Rosso and Jochen Blumberger. Electron and Hole Mobilities in Bulk Hematite from Spin-Constrained Density Functional Theory. *J. Am. Chem. Soc.* 144, 4623–4632, 2022.
- 3. **Christian S. Ahart**, Jochen Blumberger and Kevin M. Rosso. Polaronic structure of excess electrons and holes for a series of bulk iron oxides. *Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.* 22, 10699–10709, 2020.

# **Research Experience**

2022-2024 Imperial College London, UK

Research Associate

- Working to enable the dynamical modelling of electrochemical systems under applied potential by.
- Responsible for supporting PhD and Masters students with their research.

## **Education**

2018 - 2022 University College London, UK

PhD Condensed Matter and Materials Physics

### Thesis: Charge transport in bulk hematite and at the hematite/water interface

The mobility for excess electrons and electron holes in bulk hematite was calculated using spin-constrained and gap-optimised hybrid density functional theory, with comparison to calculations of charge transport at the hematite/water interface.

2014 - 2018 University of Nottingham, UK

MSc. Chemistry and Molecular Physics (First class Honours)

#### **Modules include:**

- Scientific Computing
- Quantum Dynamics
- Solids, Interfaces and Surfaces
- · Advanced Physical Chemistry

### Master's project: Quantum mechanics of rotating electron nuclear spin systems

This project involved research into, and application of, theoretical and computational techniques to model nuclear magnetic resonance with dynamic nuclear polarisation.

**2007 - 2014** William Howard School, Brampton, UK

A Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Biology AS (A)

GCSEs: 9 including Maths and English (A\*-B)

# **Teaching Experience**

2018-2021 University College London, UK

Postgraduate Teaching Assistant

- Marked coursework for lecture courses and demonstrated in computer labs.
- Gained experience in a leadership role and working as part of a larger team.

June - Aug Johns Hopkins University Centre for Talented Youth, Pennsylvania, USA 
2016 Chemistry Teaching Assistant

- Secured a position at a prestigious USA summer school for talented youths.
- Supported the planning and delivery of lessons, workshops and laboratory work; progressed to leading all aspects.

June - Aug Camp Marist, New Hampshire, USA 2015 Camp Counsellor and Photographer

- Taught photography and video editing skills to children aged 9-16; progressed to leading classes.
- Produced photographs to a high standard which were used on the camp website and in the 2016 promotional literature.

Jan 2010 - Bewcastle Scout Group, Bewcastle, UK

Jan 2014 Young Leader

- Assisted and led activities for children aged 6-14, with a focus on Cubs aged 8-10.
- Responsible for supervising Cubs during activities, including overnight camps.
- Gained the esteemed Chief Scout Platinum Award.

## **Other Skills**

- IT: Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Creative Suite, LaTeX, LINUX.
- Programming: Fortran, Python, MATLAB.
- Bronze and Silver Duke of Edinburgh's Awards.
- Full, clean driving licence (10 years).

### **Interests**

- eSports: captain of a 5-member team within the Nottingham Gaming Society competing in National tournaments.
- Homebrew: member of the London Amateur Brewers, participate in homebrew competitions.
- Rock climbing, badminton.